Scientists Collection 1563-1973 Mss.509.L56
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1563-1973; 5.0 lin. feet 10 upright boxes, 8 oversize folders.
  - Letter to Dyroff, Dr., 1926 Jul. 13; Planck, Max and Marga
  - Letter to Rolleston, Humphry Davy, 1862-1944, 1928 Feb. 28; Lankester, E. Ray, Sir, (Edwin Ray), 1847-1929
  - Letter to Gray, Joseph Alexander, 1884-1966, 1928 Apr. 29; Cave, H. M.
    1975-1332ms
  - Letter to Eisenhart, Luther Pfahler, 1876-, 1929 Feb. 2; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955
    Photostat
    1962-732ph
  - Autograph, 1929 Feb. 15; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955
  - Letter to Gray, Joseph Alexander, 1884-1966, 1929 Mar. 11; Cave, H. M.
  - Letter to Gray, Joseph Alexander, 1884-1966, 1929 Mar. 26; Cave, H. M.
  - Letter to Gray, Joseph Alexander, 1884-1966, 1929 Apr. 4; Cave, H. M.
  - Letter to Gray, Joseph Alexander, 1884-1966, 1929 Jul. 29; Cave, H. M.
  - Letter to Gray, Joseph Alexander, 1884-1966, 1929 Sep. 30; Cave, H. M.
    On same pages as 18 Nov. letter.
  - Letter to Gordon, Dean, 1929 Nov. 18; Jeans, James Hopwood, Sir, 1877-1946
  - Letter to Gray, Joseph Alexander, 1884-1966, 1929 Nov. 18; Cave, H. M.
    On same pages as 30 Sept. letter.
  - Letter to Gray, Joseph Alexander, 1884-1966, 1930 Mar. 11; Cave, H. M.
  - Letter to Gray, Joseph Alexander, 1884-1966, 1930 Mar. 14; Cave, H. M.
  - Letter to Gray, Joseph Alexander, 1884-1966, 1930 Jun. 7; O'Leary, A. J.
  - Letter to Gray, Joseph Alexander, 1884-1966, 1930 Sep. 5; Cave, H. M.
  - Letter to Faraday, W. Barnard, 1930 Dec. 8; Hadfield, Robert Abbott, Sir, 1858-1940
    1984-520ms
  - Letter to Eisenhart, Luther Pfahler, 1876-, 1930 Dec. 10; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955
  - Letter to Faraday, W. Barnard, 1930 Dec. 11; Hadfield, Robert Abbott, Sir, 1858-1940
  - Letter to Faraday, W. Barnard, 1931 Jan. 8; Hadfield, Robert Abbott, Sir, 1858-1940
  - Letter to Faraday, W. Barnard, 1931 Feb. 13; Hadfield, Robert Abbott, Sir, 1858-1940
  - Letter to Faraday, W. Barnard, 1931 Mar. 12; Hadfield, Robert Abbott, Sir, 1858-1940
  - Letter to Faraday, W. Barnard, 1931 Mar. 17; Hadfield, Robert Abbott, Sir, 1858-1940
  - Letter to Faraday, W. Barnard, 1931 Jun. 29; Hadfield, Robert Abbott, Sir, 1858-1940
  - Letter to Faraday, W. Barnard, 1931 Aug. 26; Hadfield, Robert Abbott, Sir, 1858-1940
  - Letter to Faraday, W. Barnard, 1931 Sep. 11; Hadfield, Robert Abbott, Sir, 1858-1940
  - Letter to Faraday, W. Barnard, 1931 Oct. 13; Hadfield, Robert Abbott, Sir, 1858-1940
  - Letter to Faraday, W. Barnard, 1931 Oct. 23; Hadfield, Robert Abbott, Sir, 1858-1940
  - Letter to Faraday, W. Barnard, 1931 Oct. 31; Yonatt(?)
  - Letter to Bouton, Dr., 1932 Apr. 7; Eckener, Hugo
  - Letter to Rolleston, Humphry Davy, 1862-1944, 1932 Sep. 22; Rapson, E.
  - Letter to Rolleston, Humphry Davy, 1862-1944, 1932 Sep. 24; Rapson, E.
  - Letter to Rolleston, Humphry Davy, 1862-1944, 1934 Feb. 17; O'Higgins, Edward
  - Letter to Sarnoff, David, 1935 Feb. 15; Nally, Edward Julian
  - Letter to Auchincloss, C. C., 1935 Sep. 28; Hammond, John Hays
  - Letter to Gray, Joseph Alexander, 1884-1966, 1935 Oct. 15; Marshall, Stewart
  - Letter to Clarke, James L., 1937 May 5; Mallinckrodt, Edward, Jr.
  - Letter to Clarke, Mrs. Hans T., 1937 Jun. 12; Planck, Max, 1858-1947
    1961-1884ms
    Unlocated June 2011. (Possibly misdated 1838 letter?)
  - Letter to Ross, Miss, 1937 Aug. 24; Stein, Auriol, 1862-
  - Letter to [Mrs. Hans Clarke], 1938 Jun. 12; Planck, Max, 1858-1947
    1961 1884ms. Presented by Dr. Hans Clarke, Nov. 1961.
    Includes typewritten translation.
  - Letter to Gray, Joseph Alexander, 1884-1966, 1939 Jul. 17; S., Margaret
  - Letter to Gray, Elizabeth, 1940 Jan. 20; Helen
  - Letter to Skinner, Miss, 1940 Feb. 7; Grenfell, Wilfred Thomason
  - Letter to Pleadwell, Frank L., 1940 Mar. 1; Poulton, Edward B.
  - Letter to Gray, Elizabeth, 1940 Mar. 3; O., Nelly
  - Letter to Pleadwell, Frank L., 1940 Mar. 6; Carpenter, G. D. Hale, Geoffrey Douglas Hale, (Geoffrey Douglas Hale), 1882-
  - Letter to Ording, Mr., 1940 Jun. 7; Bent, Arthur Cleveland, 1866-1954
  - Letter to Roberts, S. C., 1940 Nov. 28; Jeans, James Hopwood, Sir, 1877-1946
  - Letter to Gray, Elizabeth, 1941 May 11; Rumble, Mae
  - Letter to Waltie, 1941 Jun. 15; Lonnie
  - Letter to Allen, Michael, 1951 Oct. 29; Bush, Vannevar, 1890-1974
  - Letter to Allen, Michael, 1951 Nov. 7; Bush, Vannevar, 1890-1974
  - Letter to Pelton, Danny, 1953 May 15; Armstrong, Edwin Howard
  - Letter to Theal, 1955 Jan. 6; Alport, A. Cecil, d.1959
  - Letter to Booth, Mrs., 1955 Mar. 24; Soddy, Frederick
  - Autograph, 1959 Feb. 3; Dufell, George
  - Letter to Booth, Mr., 1959 Oct. 2; Robinson, Robert
  - Letter to Brown, George H., Jr., 1962 Jul. 23; Tykociner, Joseph Tykocinski, 1877-1969
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, 1971 Jun. 18; Barton, Derek H. R.
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, 1971 Jun. 23; Medawar, P. B. (Peter Brian), 1915-
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, 1971 Jul. 16; Todd, Lord
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, 1971 Jul. 21; Porter, George, 1920-
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, 1971 Oct. 12; Bethe, Hans A., (Hans Albrecht), 1906-2005
  - Letter to [Sir Peter Arthur Wells], 1972 Sep. 5; Birkenhead, Lord Cohen of
  - Letter to Stallard, Peter, 1972 Sep. 11; Semple, Andrew B.
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, 1973 Jan. 29; Krebs, Hans Adolf, Sir
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, 1973 Feb. 13; Hodgkin, Alan L.
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, 1973 Feb. 15; Katz, Bernard
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, 1973 Feb. 17; Moran, Lord
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, 1973 Feb. 20; Peters, Rudolph
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, 1973 Feb. 21; Gabor, Dennis
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, 1973 Feb. 23; Barton, Derek H. R.
    Separated Materials note
    Originally housed with 18 June 1971, Barton to Taylor.
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, 1973 Feb. 25; Kastler, Alfred
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, 1973 Feb. 27; Todd, Lord
    Originally housed with 16 July 1971, Todd to Taylor.
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, 1973 Mar. 1; Best, Charles H.
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, 1973 Mar. 28; Sargant, William
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Abernethy, John, 1764-1831
  - Letter to Staehli, Dr., undated; Agassiz, E. L.
  - Letter to Owen, Richard, 1804-1892, undated; Airy, George Biddell, Sir, 1801-1892
  - Letter to Panckoucke, André Joseph, 1700-1753, undated; Alembert, Jean le Rond de, 1717-1783
  - Letter to Keeneway, Mrs., undated; Anning, Mary, 1799-1847
  - Letter to Townsend, John K., undated, Jun. 12; Audubon, John James, 1785-1851
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Audouard, Olympe, 1830-1890
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Audouard, Olympe, 1830-1890
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Audouard, Olympe, 1830-1890
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Audouard, Olympe, 1830-1890
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Audouard, Olympe, 1830-1890
  - Letter to Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823, undated; Barton, Benjamin Smith, 1766-1815
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, undated; Bell, T. H.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Belleville
  - Letter to Steedman, P. A., undated; Bennett, James Risdon, 1809-1891
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Buckstone, John B.; Buckstone, John. B.
    Includes a 17 Nov. 1874 biography page for dramatists Buckstone and William Schwenck Gilbert.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Blunt, George W.
  - Letter to Harvey, Mrs. Berrison?, undated; Brewster, David, Sir, 1781-1868
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Brougham and Vaux, Henry Peter Brougham, 1778-1868
  - Letter to Wallon, undated; Cayley, Arthur, 1821-1895
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Chambers, Robert, 1802-1871
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Chambers, Robert, 1802-1871
  - Autograph, undated; Chambers, Robert, 1802-1871
  - Letter to Barbier, undated; Champollion, Jean François, 1790-1832
  - Letter to British Medical Association. President, undated; Channeau, A.
  - Letter to Lyon, John, undated; Clark, Thomas
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, undated; Clayton, Stanley
  - Letter to Cooper, A. B., undated; Crookes, William, 1832-1919
    1974 995.d ms
  - Letter to Sidney, Viscount, undated; Curtis, John
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Cuvier, Georges, Baron, 1769-1832
  - AMs, Shells from Robert Damon, undated; Damon, Robert, 1814-1889
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Danberry, Prof.
  - Note, undated; Féréol, Felix, 1825-1891
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Defrany ?
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Donato, Louis
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Donato, Louis
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Dumas, J.-B., (Jean-Baptiste), 1800-1884
    1975 737ms.
    In French.
  - Letter to Gillet de Laumont, François Pierre Nicolas, 1747-1834, undated; Dupuget, Edme Jean Antoine, comte, 1742-1801
  - Letter to Eisenhart, Luther Pfahler, 1876-, undated; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955
  - Mathematical manuscript, undated; Emerson, William, 1701-1782
  - Autograph, undated; Field, Cyrus W. (Cyrus West), 1819-1892
  - Letter to Simon, Mr., undated; Finter, W. L.
  - Letter to Dunn, Robert, undated; Flower, William Henry, 1831-1899
  - Letter to Poulton, Edward, 1856-1943, undated; Foster, Michael, 1836-1907
  - Calling card, undated; Franklin, John, Sir, 1786-1847
  - Letter to Geoffroy Saint-Hillaire, Étienne, 1772-1844, undated; Gay-Lussac, Joseph Louis, 1878-1950
  - Letter to Seaton, William Winston, undated; Gilliss, James Melville
  - Letter to Noble, John, undated; Gould, John
  - Letter to Owen, Robert, undated; Green, Joseph H., 1791-1663
  - Letter to Ward, Miss, undated; Guthrie, George James, 1785-1856
  - Autograph presentation note to Charles J. Folger, undated; Hall, James
  - Autograph presentation note...Thurlow Weed, undated; Hall, James
  - Letter to Clark, James?, undated; Harland, Arethusa Vernon
  - Letter to Ross, Mr., undated; Harland, Arethusa Vernon
    Donation of £10 for "the poor afflicted widow."
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
  - Astronomical notes, undated; Herschel, John F. W., Sir, (John Frederick William), 1792-1871
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Hewet, Stanley
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Hope, Mrs.
  - Letter to Parnell, Mr., undated; Hotham
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Note, undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Memoir of Frederick Rudolph Hassler, undated; Ingham, Samuel Delucenna, 1779-1860
  - Autograph, undated; Jeans, James Hopwood, Sir, 1877-1946
  - Letter to Vulliamy, Benjamin Lewis, 1780-1854, undated; Kaye, Eliza Mortlock
  - Addressed envelope, undated; King, Peter King, Lord, 1776-1833
  - Letter to Hare, Mrs., undated; Kusler, E.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Lacock, C.
  - Letter to Gray, Asa, 1810-1888, undated; Lapham, J. A.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Lardner, Dionysius, 1793-1859
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Lardner, Dionysius, 1793-1859
  - Letter to Colletti(?), Dr., undated; Lardner, Dionysius, 1793-1859
  - Autograph, undated; Lesseps, Ferdinand de
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, undated; Lindley, John
  - Letter to "Sir or Madam", undated; Lodge, Oliver, Sir, 1851-1940
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated Aug. 29; Lubbock, John, Sir, 1834-1913
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated Nov. 21; Lubbock, John, Sir, 1834-1913
  - Letter to Beck, J., undated Jun. 5; Lubbock, John, Sir, 1834-1913
  - Letter to Vincent, Mr., undated Jun. 1; Lubbock, John, Sir, 1834-1913
  - Letter to Wilson, C. R., undated Jun. 1; Lubbock, John, Sir, 1834-1913
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated Jan. 9; Luys, Jules, 1828-1897
    Saturday.
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, undated; Lyell, Mary E.
  - Letter to Staehli, Dr., undated; Lyman, Theodore, 1833-1897
  - Autograph, undated; MacMillan, Donald
  - Autograph, undated; Maxim, Hiram S.
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, undated; Medawar, P. B. (Peter Brian), 1915-
    Originally foldered with 23 June 1971, Medawar to Taylor.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Mully, Gruneau de
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated May 9; Nadaillac, Jean François Albert du Pouget, marquis de, 1818-1904
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated Jul. 8; Nadaillac, Jean François Albert du Pouget, marquis de, 1818-1904
  - Letter to Mason, Otis Tufton, 1838-1908, undated Aug. 16; Nadaillac, Jean François Albert du Pouget, marquis de, 1818-1904
  - Letter to Mason, Otis Tufton, 1838-1908, undated Sep. 21; Nadaillac, Jean François Albert du Pouget, marquis de, 1818-1904
  - Letter to Mason, Otis Tufton, 1838-1908, undated Dec. 18; Nadaillac, Jean François Albert du Pouget, marquis de, 1818-1904
  - Letter to Mason, Otis Tufton, 1838-1908, undated; Nadaillac, Jean François Albert du Pouget, marquis de, 1818-1904
  - Letter to Miscellaneous notes, undated; Newton, Alfred, 1829-1907
  - TMs, Atomic Constituents of Nature, undated; Northrop, F. S. C., (Filmer Stuart Cuckow), 1893-
  - Letter to Wheatley, Henry, undated; Osler, William, Sir, 1849-1919
  - Letter to Laddiges, George, undated; Parkinson, Richard
  - Letter to Peale, Franklin, undated; Patterson,, Robert M., (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Autograph, undated; Peary, Robert E.
    Mounted with portrait.
  - Letter to Koster, J. T., undated; Pond, John
  - List of shells, undated; Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-
    1965 2170ms, 509L56.po.
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, undated; Prime, Temple, 1832-1903
  - List of publications, undated; Proctor, Richard A.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated Aug. 24; Ruggles, Mrs. T. E.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Ruggles, Mrs. T. E.
  - Autograph, undated; Russell, John Scott
  - Autograph, undated; Salk, Jonas, 1914-1995
    Salk's autograph added to "A Poetrait of Dr. Jonas E. Salk," an acrostic poem by Jimmie Grice.
  - Letter to Taylor, A. Nelson, undated; Sanger, Frederick
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Seeley, John Robert
  - Letter to Bailey, L. M., undated; Stimpson, William, 1832-1872
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Swartz, Olaf
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, undated; Thirwall, Connop, Bishop of St. David's
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Tholozar, Joseph Desiré, 1831-1897
  - Letter to Hart, Mr., undated; Thompson, Henry, 1820-1904
  - Letter to Hart, Mr., undated; Thompson, Henry, 1820-1904
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Tyndall, John, 1820-1893
  - Letter to Leighton, Mr., undated; Tyndall, John, 1820-1893
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Waterhouse
  - Letter to Bessey, Charles E. (Charles Edwin), 1845-1915, undated; Wetherby, A. G.
  - Ticket of Admission to Mr. Gregsen and Mr. Evans., undated; Whewell, William, 1794-1866
  - Note, undated; Whewell, William, 1794-1866
  - AMsS, The future of horticulture, undated; White, William N., 1819-1867
  - Letter to Gray, Elizabeth, undated Jan. 14; Williams, Rachel L.
  - Letter to Gray, Elizabeth, undated Mar. 1; Williams, Rachel L.
  - Letter to Gray, Elizabeth, undated Oct. 2; Williams, Rachel L.
  - Letter to Gray, Elizabeth, undated Oct. 7; Williams, Rachel L.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Wilson, William James Erasmus, 1809-1884
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Woods, Henry C.
  - Letter to Barlow, undated; Yarrell, William, 1784-1856
  - Books which belonged to James Keoppoch Hamilton, 66 New York City... " an enthusiastic amateur botanist.", undated; Unidentified author
  - Concerning Olympe Audouard, undated; Unidentified author
    Audouard, Olympe, 1830-1890
  - Evolution (a poem), undated; Unidentified author
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, undated; Unidentified author
  - List of Helices wanted, undated; Unidentified author
- Series II. American-Russian Scientific Correspondence, 1789-1910; 0.25 lin. feet 1 upright box.
  Photographs of correspondence relating to American and Russian scientific exchange prior to the Russian Revolution. The letters are a scattered and presumably incomplete representation of materials housed in the Akademiia Nauk S.S.S.R.
  Original documents housed in the Akademiia Nauk S.S.S.R.
  - Letter to Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790, 1789 Nov.; 509 L56.m; Académie imperiale des sciences de St. Petersbourg.
    St. Petersbourg, Photo.of L.S.: Jean Albert Euler. 2p. In French. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Notifies him of his election and praises him.
  - Table of contents, 509 L56.m
  - Letter to Herschel, William, 1789 Nov.; 509 L56.m; Académie imperiale des sciences de St. Petersbourg.
    St. Petersbourg, Photo.of L.S.: Jean Albert Euler. 1p. In French. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Notifies him of his election.
  - Letter to Académie Imperiale des Sciences de St. Petersbourg. President, 1790 Oct. 22; 509 L56.m; Churchman, John, 1753-1805
    Philadelphia, Photo.of A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Concerning magnetism and longitude. Forwards his chart of variations of the compas.
  - Letter to Académie Imperiale des Sciences de St. Petersbourg. President, 1793 Jul. 12; 509 L56.m; Churchman, John, 1753-1805
    London, Photo.of A.L.S. 4p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Concerning books sent to the APS. His work on the compas and variations on the compass.
  - Letter to Clarke, Alexander Ross, 1828-1914, 1829 Feb. 24; 509 L56.m; Unidentified author
  - Letter to Struve, F. G. W. (Friedrich Georg Wilhelm), 1793-1864, 1857 Dec. 24; 509 L56.m; Clarke, Alexander Ross, 1828-1914
    Southampton, Photo.of A.L.S. 3p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Questions figures in triangulations.
  - Letter to Struve, F. G. W. (Friedrich Georg Wilhelm), 1793-1864, 1858 May 7; 509 L56.m; Clarke, Alexander Ross, 1828-1914
    Southampton, Eng., Photo.of A.L.S. 1p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Has forwarded account of the triangulation of Great Britain.
  - Letter to Struve, F. G. W. (Friedrich Georg Wilhelm), 1793-1864, 1861 Jun. 4; 509 L56.m; Clarke, Alexander Ross, 1828-1914
    Southampton, Photo.of A.L.S. 5p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Triangulation.
  - Letter to Struve, F. G. W. (Friedrich Georg Wilhelm), 1793-1864, 1864 Jun. 17; 509 L56.m; Clarke, Alexander Ross, 1828-1914
    Southampton, Photo.of L. 4p. (see Letters of scientists. Moscow..) Determination of latitude and longitude Refers to Airy. Triangulation.
  - Letter to Struve, F. G. W. (Friedrich Georg Wilhelm), 1793-1864, 1864 Oct. 19; 509 L56.m; Clarke, Alexander Ross, 1828-1914
    Southampton, Photo.of A.L.S. 4p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Concerning the shipment of the standard bar.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1864 Nov. 17; 509 L56.m; Clarke, Alexander Ross, 1828-1914
    Southampton, Photo.of A.L.S. 1p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Since navigation to St. Petersburg is now closed, he expects they will not receive the standard bar until next spring.
  - Letter to Académie imperiale des sciences de St. Petersbourg., 1865 Mar. 3; 509 L56.m; Adams, John Couch, 1819-1892
    Cambridge, Photo.of A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Letters of Scientists, Moscow...) Thanks for being made a member. Refers to Euler.
  - Letter to Veselovsky, Aleksandr Nikblaevich, 1865 Jul. 2; 509 L56.m; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895
    London, Photo.of L. 1p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscwo...) Thanks to the Imperial Academy for having been made a member. Unlocated June 2011.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1865 Jul. 15; 509 L56.m; Clarke, Alexander Ross, 1828-1914
    Southampton, Photo.of A.L.S. 2p. (see Letters of scientists. Moscow...) Asks for error in the stardard bar.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1867 Sep. 5; 509 L56.m; Clarke, Alexander Ross, 1828-1914
    Southampton, Photo.of A.L.S. 4p. (see Letters of scientists. Moscow...) Variations on the bar.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1867 Dec. 30; 509 L56.m; Clarke, Alexander Ross, 1828-1914
    Southampton, Photo.of A.L.S. 1p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Thanks for the favor conferred on him by the academy of sciences.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1868 Apr. 13; 509 L56.m; Clarke, Alexander Ross, 1828-1914
    Southampton, Photo.of A.L.S. 6p. (see Letters of scientists. Moscow...) His observations with the bars. Refers to Airy.
  - Letter to Radsoff, Mr., 1869 Apr. 30; 509 L56.m; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Washington, Photo.of A.L.S. 1p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Will ship publications, but would like direction for shipping.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1878 Oct. 8; 509 L56.m; Clarke, Alexander Ross, 1828-1914
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1878 Dec. 23; 509 L56.m; Clarke, Alexander Ross, 1828-1914
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1879 Apr. 18; 509 L56.m; Clarke, Alexander Ross, 1828-1914
    Photo.of A.L.S. 4p. (see Letters of scientists. Moscow...) Geodetic association. Pendulum.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1881 Mar. 15; 509 L56.m; Clarke, Alexander Ross, 1828-1914
    Hastings, Photo.of A.L.S. 4p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Has been retired and needs extra income.
  - Letter to Salemann, Karl Germanovich, 1849-1916, 1887 Sep. 24; 509 L56.m; Jackson, Abraham Valentine Wiliams, 1862-1937
    Halle, Ger., Photo. of A.L.S. 1p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Thanks for his publication and forwards one of his own.
  - Letter to Salemann, Karl Germanovich, 1849-1916, 1888 May 16; 509 L56.m; Jackson, Abraham Valentine Wiliams, 1862-1937
    Halle, Ger., Photo. of A.L.S. 2p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Forwards article on oriental writings.
  - Letter to Salemann, Karl Germanovich, 1849-1916, 1889 Jul. 30; 509 L56.m; Jackson, Abraham Valentine Wiliams, 1862-1937
    Halle, Ger., Photo. of A.L.S. on postal card. 1p.and add. (see Letters of scientists. Moscow...) Thanks for his publication.
  - Letter to Salemann, Karl Germanovich, 1849-1916, 1889 Sep. 18; 509 L56.m; Jackson, Abraham Valentine Wiliams, 1862-1937
    New York, Photo. of A.L.S. 1p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Thanks for his publication and forwards his own publication on oriental literature
  - Letter to Rost, Dr., 1891 Jan. 19; 509 L56.m; Mitchell, J. Murray, (John Murray), 1815-1904
    Nice, Photo.of A.L.S. 2p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Tells him of a merchant in the city who has an oriental manuscript, but does not know the language.
  - Letter to Belopolsky, A., 1899 Jun. 29; 509 L56.m; Young, Charles Augustus, 1834-1908
    Princeton, N. J., Photo.of A.L.S. 2p. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Is delighted that he will visit the observatory at Princeton.
  - Letter to Salemann, Karl Germanovich, 1849-1916, 1901 Jul. 31; 509 L56.m; Jackson, Abraham Valentine Wiliams, 1862-1937
    New York, Photo. of A.L.S. on postal card. 1p.and add. (see Letters of Scientists. Moscow...) Has just returned from Indian. Congratulates him on a publication.
  - Letter to Salemann, Karl Germanovich, 1849-1916, 1903 Jan. 31; 509 L56.m; Jackson, Abraham Valentine Wiliams, 1862-1937
    New York, Photo.of Printed and A.L.S. 1p. (see Letters of scientists. Moscow...) Dr. Jackson is on the way to Iran.
  - Letter to Salemann, Karl Germanovich, 1849-1916, 1903 Jun. 15; 509 L56.m; Jackson, Abraham Valentine Wiliams, 1862-1937